<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Mechalit Equipment + Faction 1.2</name>
  <author>Daniledman</author>
  <packageId>Daniledman.MechalitEquipment</packageId>
  <description>							 
This is the second mod in the "Mechalit" mod series, and also a prepartional one before the third mod, that will add Mechalit faction itself and some new powerful mechanoids.
Mechalit Eqipment is focused mainly on textile and weaponry: adds synthread and hyperweave crafting recipes,
new types of textile and a wey to craft them, new equpment and weapons of the Mechalit faction. New hi-tech stuff should make game more enjoyable on later stages.
The mod is compatible with old saves and doesn't require new game, but Mechalit Core mod is needed.

FEATURES:
-8 new research projects
-new mecha-workbench
-ability to process unneeded skin into special material, and then - into synthread and hyperweave
-synthread and hyperweave craft
-new apparel
-new helmets and armor
-new futuristic weapons with unique sound effects

-SYNTHREAD AND HYPERWEAVE CRAFT:
 Both synthread and hyperweave are now available for craft on mecha-workbench, but it will require big amount of multicloth and other resources.
 (For balance, market value of hyperweave was lowered from 16 to 8)

-NEW TYPES OF FABRICS:
 -Multicloth - made from cloth or skin, using the N-16 gas (from the Mechalit Core mod). Can't be used to craft clothes. Can be used to make synthread.
 -Thermothread - a semi-synthetic textile with great insulating properties. Made from synthread and wool.
 -Mechaweave - a hi-tech textile, made from hyperweave and devilstrand. Gives good protection both from damage and extreme temperatures.

-NEW SUITS:
 Suits cover the whole body and take 2 clothing slots (shirt and pants).
 -Thermosuit - fully covers the body, keeping its temperature normal. Greatly protects from heat and cold, but offers almost no damage reduction.
 -Protective suit - covers the whole body, protecting it from various types of damage. Slighly reduces movement and work speeds.
 -Worker's exosuit - covers the whole body. Grants little protection, but increases movement and work speeds thanks to built-in servos.
 
-NEW BELTS:
 -Train belt - It is attached to the waist and connects to the spinal cord. It facilitates the rapid assimilation of information and the improvement of muscle memory, and therefore increases the learning factor for everything.
 Side effects: reduces the speed of work, the rate of absorption of food, increases the threshold of nervous breakdown. The training belt is necessary for colonists with a low level of any skill in order to develop it as quickly as possible.
 
-NEW HELMETS AND MECHALIT FACTION ARMOR SET:
 -Tactical helmet - an advanced helmet with visor. Protects your head and makes you shots more accurate.
 -"Puma" helmet - an advanced tactical software enhances fighter's melee efficiency, while special covering protects from psi-effects. Offers small protection, compared to power armor helmet.
 -Mechalit helmet - a high-tech helmet with visor and psi-protection. Offers good protection against all types of damage. High-class tactical software assits in aiming and learning.
 -Mechalit armor - a hi-tech piece of armor with mechanite controlled life support system. Greatly increases wearer's survival rate and boosts many of his stats.
 
-NEW WEAPONS:
 -"Amber" pistol - good damage and fire rate.
 -"Neptune" SMG - cheap, low damage, but high fire rate. 
 -Plasmagun - two-barreled plasma rifle. Deals average damage over a long distance.
 -"Flash" - shoots pieces of hot metal. Sometimes can set the target on fire.
 -"Dolphin" shotgun - deals huge damage on short distances.
 -Mecharifle - a Mechalit sniper rifle. Good rate of fire and average damage.
 -Training Rifle - Has low DPS, but at the same time it is aimed at the target, practically without the participation of the owner. Due to the very high rate of fire it allows you to quickly increase the shooting skill of the owner, it is perfect for pawns with low shooting skills.
 -"Eclipse" machinegun - very rare and expensive to make. Deals huge damage, but psi-active artifacts in it can cause behavioral instability.
 -"Lord" - A powerful cannon that shoots clusters of clean energy. Has a low range of fire, but very high damage.
 
 -NEW MELEE WEAPONS:
 -"Rapier" - Easy plasma blade. Does not do great damage, but has a high attack speed. Thanks to the built-in micro-turbines, the blade increases the speed of the owner's movement.
 
-NEW FACTION "MECHALIT"
 -High-tech warlike ancient faction. Members of the faction are aggressive to strangers, but love money. Therefore, you can still make friends with them, but you have to pay dearly.
The faction has mastered the high technologies that made it possible to create weapons that are stronger than power grips. But not all members of the faction are armed with the latest technology, because there are ranks in the faction. Only elite fighters of the faction deserve to wear the best armor and equipment. The bulk of the fighters of the faction — warriors and destroyers — are well equipped, but they are slightly weaker than those of elite warriors.
Scout factions are most often used in raids on young settlements and in most cases do not pose a particular threat, but even among scouts there are strong fighters with good cannons. The france warriors sometimes set themselves for artificial limbs.
The faction has long been using reprogrammed mechanoids to accompany their warriors. The leadership of the faction considered the ulans the most useful mechanoids. Therefore, the fraction uses improved modifications of the ulans created with the help of drawings of captured mechanoids. New mechanoids of the faction got a bright war paint to be more noticeable in battle and distract the enemy to themselves.
The leadership of the Mechalit faction does not allow the faction’s equipment and armament to reach the less developed “not worthy” civilizations, therefore it obliges all fighters of the faction to wear special nano-teleporters who teleport all fighters and equipment from the battlefield. But this does not mean that you will be left with nothing. In place of defeated enemies remain resources from their inventories. Even ordinary fighters of the faction are quite rich and they always have some kind of resource.
 
</description>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.0</li>
    <li>1.1</li>
    <li>1.2</li>
  </supportedVersions>
</ModMetaData>